なんばむった
ジャクサうちゅうひこうしせんばつ
＜JAXAの宇宙飛行士選抜試験も➡
The second round of the JAXA astronaut selection exam has begun.
いよいよ第２ラウンドだ！
ところが私 南波六太は➡
However, I've discovered
ひびと
宇宙飛行士 南波日々人の
めいわく
兄として はた迷惑な注目を➡
that the other applicants are paying extra attention to me
because I, Nanba Mutta, happen to be astronaut Nanba Hibito's older brother.
周りの人々から浴びていることを
知ってしまった＞
＜果たして この試験を乗り越え➡
Will I be able to survive this exam,
宇宙を目指すことが
できるのだろうか!?＞
and make it to space?
Space Brothers
Ah
This feels so good, different from usual
I have no idea what's going on
It feels so good
I never understand what's going on around me
Nothing makes sense to me
Full of questions
Feel so moon
I danced with you in a desert lit by the moon
I won't lose to the rabbit and fly high
I'll fly high
#04 Next to Hibito
ご安心下さい｡
これは事故ではありません｡➡
Don't worry.
This isn't an accident.
ご覧の映像は 来年
打ち上げが予定されている➡
You're looking at the moon base team's zero-g training
きちけんせつ
月面基地建設チームの
むじゅうりょくくんれん
無重力訓練の１つです｡
for next year's mission.
(ﾚﾎﾟｰﾀｰ)高度１万メートル上空から
急降下し➡
By diving sharply from ten thousand meters,
約３０秒間の無重力状態を
体験します｡
they can experience thirty seconds of zero gravity.
(カレン)ハ～イ！
Hi!
ワ～オ！
Wow!
この訓練では 宇宙酔い状態になり
中には オエップしてしまう人も｡
During this training, some astronauts
get space-sick and throw up.
そんな中 今回一番
元気そうだったのは この人！➡
And now, we'll introduce today's most animated astronaut!
ミスター ヒビト･ナンバ！
Mr. Hibito Nanba!
ふくざつ
《ムッ君…複雑だろうな》
It must be awkward for Mu.
(せりか)《兄弟で宇宙飛行士を
目指すなんて》
Both brothers aim to become astronauts.
《うらやましいぜ 日々人》
I'm jealous, Hibito...
《お前の…お前の…➡
You have...
お前の後ろに美女が２人も！》
You have two hot babes behind you!
Makabe, please come to interview room 2.
まかべ
真壁さん 第ニ面接室へどうぞ｡
はい！行ってくるよ｡
Yes, sir.
Wish me luck.
お…おう！
Y-Yeah.
《青春してやがる》
He's having too much fun.
フゥ～｡
After this final interview, the second exam ends.
《いよいよ この最終面接で
二次試験は全て終わる｡➡
長かった一週間が終わるのだ｡
いな
そして 私が合格するか否かは…➡
The long week will finally be over...
And whether I pass or fail
この面接に かかっていると
言っていいのだ！》
rests on this interview!
Thank you very much.
≪ありがとうございました≫
失礼します｡
I'll excuse myself.
ふぅ～ 終わった…｡
It's over...
I belong up there!
《あの場所は 僕になるはずだ！》
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much.
Yes! It's over!
《よっしゃ～！終わった!!》
What should I have to eat?
《お父さん…
ここにはきっと私が》
Dad...
I'll make it here
one day...
(係員)南波さん 第二面接室へ｡
Nanba, please come to interview room 2.
え ハイ！
Yes, sir!
《こう見えてもな
私は面接には慣れた方だ｡➡
You'd never guess that I'm so experienced with interviews.
だって この最終面接の前に
せんもんちしき
英語面接や専門知識面接➡
I mean, there was an English interview, a technical interview,
せいしん
精神面接なんてものもあったのだ｡
一体 何回 面接すんだ？➡
and a psychological interview, all before this final one.
How many times will they interview us?
中でも まるで取り調べみたいな
精神面接では 面接官が怖い！》
And the psychological interview felt like an interrogation.
That interviewer scared me!
(面接官)((君 若い頃に
万引きしたことは？))
As a child, did you ever shoplift?
(面接官)((一度ぐらいあるんじゃ
ないですか？))
Surely you shoplifted once?
((うぐっ))
Well?
((え～ え～っと))
Uh... Well...
《あれ？ここって
ＪＡＸＡだよな？➡
Huh? This is JAXA, right?
ケンジに聞いてみた》
I asked Kenji about it.
What was up with that scary interviewer?
((ハッハハ｡あれ たぶん面接官の
ひそ
中に 密かにいるんだよ｡➡
They probably snuck him in.
一流の心理学者とか
ぶんせきい
精神分析医がね｡➡
He's likely some expert in psychology and psychoanalysis.
それで 質問にも強弱をつけて
気付かないうちに➡
So he asked us loaded questions
to discover what we were thinking deep inside.
しんそう
僕らの深層心理を引っ張り
出そうとしてるんだろうな))
((猫かぶっていい人ぶってても➡
He can tell if you're putting on an act.
彼らには
見抜かれてるってことだよ))
(面接官)≪どうぞ≫
Come in.
失礼します！
Excuse me!
《どうしよ ケンジ》
What should I do, Kenji?
New Astronaut
Selection
Interview Room
New Astronaut
Selection
Interview Room
今あるものに満足することなく
ちょうせん
挑戦し続けること｡
I'm never content with myself,
so I'm always looking for my next challenge.
こうきしん
みち
未知なるものへの好奇心こそが
そんげん
人間の尊厳かと…｡
Humans are defined by their thirst for the unknown.
I've been acting this entire time...
《猫かぶりまくりだよ 俺｡
今もなお》
I still am.
ニャ～ッ｡
(面接官)なるほど わかりました｡
Very well... I understand.
なすだ
(茄子田)それでは最後に
あたくしから｡
I have one final question for you.
英語
Did you find something new about yourself recently?
は…発見ですか？
《なんだよ あんた!?》
F-Find something?
Who are you?
Find. Find. Find.
He suddenly switched to English, but his question doesn't make much sense.
《急に英語に切り替えたうえに
よくわからない質問だ！➡
自分のことで発見だって!?》
Find something new about myself?
え～あ～｡
《は…早くなんか答えないと》
Hurry up...
Come up with an answer.
六太の妄想
(面接官たち)((発見 発見…))
《どうする…え～ どうする？》
What do I do?
Uh, what do I do?
六太の妄想
((フッフッフッフッ))
(面接官たち)((発見 発見…))
私は！
I...
失礼します！
Excuse me!
Yeah...
《まぁ…まぁまぁまぁ｡➡
Yeah, yeah, yeah...
割といいんじゃねぇか？➡
That wasn't too bad.
びみょう
最後のは微妙だが 全体的には
うまく答えられた気がするぞ｡➡
My last answer was shaky, but I think I did well overall.
あとは結果を待つのみか…》
All that's left is waiting for the results.
お？あっ｡
もうり
毛利さん…お？
Mohri...
Oh, that's Mukai!
おぉ～ 向井さん！土井さん！
若田さんに 野口さん！
Doi!
Noguchi and Wakata!
ゆい
古川さん 星出さん 油井さん
大西さん 金井さんもいる！
Furukawa and Hoshide.
Yui and Ohnishi.
Even Kanai is here!
《そうだよな…
そりゃいるよな 日々人》
Naturally... Of course you're here,
Hibito.
なかなかキマってるじゃね～か｡
You're lookin' pretty sharp.
Oh?
まだ空いてるみたいだな
となり
お前の隣｡
There's still plenty of room next to you.
《次はこのスペースに 誰かが…》
I wonder who will end up in that spot.
《おぉ～！見えてきた!!》
I can see it!
《やっぱり そうだよなぁ》
That's how it should be.
《せっかくここまで
来たんだもんなぁ｡➡
I've made it this far.
弟の隣に 兄がいなくて
どうすんだよ｡なあ！》
An older brother should be next to his younger brother.
Right?
《ここは俺の場所だ！》
That's my spot!
ツバつけとこ｡
I'll mark it.
しんせい
(南波日々人)申請？何の？
Application?
For what?
しえん
(職員)家族支援プログラムだよ｡➡
For the family support program.
You're the only one who hasn't applied yet.
まだ申請してないのは
日々人ぐらいだぞ｡
Huh?
(職員)君たち宇宙飛行士が
にんむ
任務に集中できるよう➡
NASA provides support for astronauts, so they can focus on their missions.
ナサ
ＮＡＳＡは色々
ケアしてるんだろ？
家族支援プログラムを使えば
あなたたちの家族を呼び寄せて➡
Through the family support program,
you can bring your family here, to live with you in Houston.
このヒューストンで
一緒に生活できるのよ｡
そうなの？
Really?
俺んとこは ロスから
カミさんと子ども達がくる｡➡
My wife and kids are moving here from LA.
だんな
リンダは旦那と弟を
呼んだって言ってたな｡
Linda mentioned that her husband and brother will be coming.
フレディなんて 何人もいる彼女の
中から 誰を呼ぶかで迷ってたぜ｡
Freddy's trying to decide which girlfriend to invite.
日々人だけ
一人ぼっちでどうするの？
You'll be the only one who's alone.
そ～だなぁ｡
That's true...
じゃあまず 一人分だけ
お願いしようかな｡
Then I guess I'll apply for one person.
Only one?
(職員)一人でいいのね？
Yeah.
ＮＡＳＡのみんなには
会っとくべきだもんね｡
I'll need to introduce him to everyone at NASA.
だって もしかしたら➡
Because you might end up working with him.
僕らの仕事仲間に
なるかもしれないからな｡
(面接官)若さで見れば
だんぜん
みぞぐち
断然 溝口君でしょう｡➡
Out of the younger candidates, Mizoguchi is clearly the most qualified.
スピーチ力もあるし 申し分ない｡
He was very eloquent. I could find no fault.
Makabe was also impressive.
(面接官)真壁君もいいですよね｡
火星探査を 誰より
熱望しているのが伝わりました｡
Among the candidates, he showed the most enthusiasm for Mars exploration.
(面接官)Ｂ班は
ゆうしゅう
優秀な人が多いなぁ｡
Group B had many talented applicants.
でもやっぱり 今回の主役は
この人だなって思いましたよ｡
But the star was definitely this one.
そうめい
僕もそう思う｡聡明だしね｡
I agree. She is quite bright.
英会話でも表現力あったよ｡
And she was able to fully express herself in English.
(二村)伊東せりかさん｡
Itou Serika.
(３人)《しかも美人だし…》
Plus, she's beautiful.
(星加)彼なんてどうですか？
What about him?
Huh?
私はいいと思ったんですが…｡
I liked him.
お兄ちゃんねぇ～｡
Ah...
The older brother...
Okay, everyone!
それでは皆さ～ん！
こちらに集合して下さい｡
Please assemble over here!
A group picture of all the applicants?
いや～集合写真の記念撮影なんて
学生の頃にかえったみたいですね｡
I feel like I'm back in high school!
I'll have to tell my son when he returns.
(受験生)息子が帰ったら
自慢してやりますよ｡
(青竹)南波く～ん！
うん？青竹さん｡
Nanba!
Aotake.
ねぇ 南波君
今度 日々人君に➡
Say, Nanba,
would you please ask Hibito for an autograph?
サイン頼んどいて
もらえないかな～？
｢フミちゃんへ｣って
書いてもらえたら➡
I'd really appreciate it if you'd have him make it out to Fumi.
すごい嬉しいんだけど｡
あっ いいですよ｡なんなら
キスマークもつけさせますよ｡
Sure.
I'll even ask him to kiss it for you.
ン～マッ！
Really?!
ホントに!?
やった～！うれし～い！
Yes! I'm so thrilled!
Thank you!
ありがとう！
It's nothing...
Ah!
《わかってるさ
しょせん
俺は所詮 南波日々人の➡
I know...
I'm nothing more than Nanba Hibito's older brother.
お兄ちゃんでしかない｡
よくあることさ》
Happens all the time.
Hey, Serika!
(青竹)ねぇねぇ せりかちゃん
日々人君のサイン➡
He's going to get Hibito's autograph for me!
もらえるんだって！
せりかちゃんも もらいなよ｡
You should go ask for one, Serika.
Oh?
えっ 本当ですか？
Is that really okay?
えっ…もちろんですとも！
B-But of course.
(係員)早くしてください！
Hurry up!
Okay, move closer together!
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)は～い 皆さん
もうちょいくっついて！
《えっ でも待てよ
ってことは せりかさんまで➡
But wait!
Does that mean Serika is also one of Hibito's fans?
日々人ファンなわけ？
くっそ～ 日々人め！》
Damn you, Hibito!
《まっいいや》
Whatever.
《せりかさんには➡
I will be the one who kisses Serika's autograph.
俺のキスマークをつけよ》
(ｶﾒﾗﾏﾝ)は～い じゃあ撮ります！
Okay, say "cheese"!
《長かった二次試験は終わった》
The long second exam was finally over.
Okay, let's get drunk!
さあ 皆さん飲みましょう！
Cheers!
(一同)カンパ～イ！
でね 何回も面接やったから
わかっちゃったよ｡
So, after all those interviews, I finally figured it out.
You can't stop and think about what to say.
ああいうのは
答えを選んでちゃダメだね｡
最初に浮かんだことが正解だよ｡
The correct answer is the first thing that pops into your head.
That may be the case.
そうかもしれないなぁ｡
僕も ムッ君の言う通り
インスピレーションで答えたよ｡
I agree with Mu.
Follow your inspiration.
だろ？
あっ そういや➡
Right?
Oh, yeah...
あれ 何て答えた？
How did you answer that one question?
あれ？
That one question?
((Did you find something new
about yourself,recently?))
Did you find something new about yourself recently?
最近 自分のことで
何か発見したことは？
"Did you find something new about yourself recently?"
ああ～ 訊かれた訊かれた！
え～っとね 僕は…➡
Oh, I remember that one!
Uh, I said...
小説のような作り物は科学的では
ない｡だから これまで自分は➡
Novels are fictional and not scientific.
That is why I only read nonfiction books.
ﾉﾝﾌｨｸｼｮﾝ系の本しか読まなかった｡
だけど 友人が作家になった事が➡
However, when one of my friends became an author,
きっかけで 最近小説も読むように
なった…という話をしたんだ｡
I began reading fiction.
That was the personal experience I used.
フィクションであれ
ノンフィクションであれ➡
After all, whether it is fiction or nonfiction, someone had to write it down.
実直に作っている人がいる｡
そのことを認め➡
Once I realized that and gave it a try,
率直に触れてみれば 何であれ
新鮮で楽しく受け入れられる｡➡
I became able to enjoy reading fiction.
そんな 自分の新たな一面を
発見しましたってね｡
And so, I discovered a new side to myself.
Oh.
いい答えじゃないか｡
That's a good answer.
常日頃から自分のことに
注目しているか 自己管理能力を➡
That question was to determine whether
you pay close attention to your own behavior.
問われるような質問だよね｡
ムッ君は何て答えたの？
What did you say, Mu?
Hmm?
ん!?俺もまぁ そんな感じの答え
だったよ｡忘れちゃったけど…｡
Well, my answer was something along those lines.
I forget what it was, though.
((わ 私は！))
I...
((みんなよりシャンプーが
よく泡立ちます))
make more bubbles than anyone else when I lather my shampoo.
《わざわざ面接で
言うことじゃねえ！》
Why would I say that during an interview?
《終わった…確実に落ちた》
I screwed up.
It's all over for me...
《さよなら…皆さん》
Goodbye,
everyone...
《さよなら…ＪＡＸＡ》
Goodbye,
JAXA...
《さよなら…宇宙》
space.
《さよなら…俺》
Goodbye,
me.
(受験生)はい 送信｡
Okay, sent.
Ah, there it is.
Computer and cell phone both work.
パソコンでも携帯でも
大丈夫だから｡
Tsk.
チッ！いいなぁ
アドレス交換｡
Must be nice being able to exchange addresses.
俺も携帯持ってたんだけどなぁ～｡
If I had a cell phone...
あの～…｡
Excuse me.
Hmm?
南波さんも
アドレス交換しませんか？
Would you like to exchange e-mail addresses?
《せりかさん!?》
Serika...
おっ あっ いや！
その…それが 携帯流しちゃって｡
Oh! Er, well...
I flushed my phone...
流す？
あ～！じゃなかった｡
Flushed?
Wait, that's not it!
あの 壊してしまいまして…｡
I broke it...
Oh, really...
ああ～ そうなんですか｡
残念ですね｡
That's unfortunate.
はぁ 残念です｡すごく｡
Yes, it is...
Very.
(受験生)伊東さん｡
Itou!
ア アドレス教えてもらえますか？
W-Would you tell me your e-mail address?
Oh, sure.
あっ はい｡
Ah!
《くそっ！せっかくの
せりかさんとの会話を…》
Damn!
I finally got a chance to talk to Serika...
What?
《この…おのれ…》
Damn it!
《ったく！食べたら
空入れに入れろよな～！》
Don't put empty pods back in!
《これも！これも！》
There's one! And another one!
(ケンジ)ムッ君｡
あぁん!?
Mu.
Eh?
ほら これ｡➡
Here, you go.
みんなのアドレス メモったから｡
I wrote down everyone's e-mail addresses.
《すっ すっごい！➡
W-Wow!
Itou Serika
せりかさんのまで
あるじゃないか！》
He even got Serika's address!
新しい携帯を買ったら
登録するといいよ｡
Once you get a new phone, you should add them.
ケンジ～！
Kenji!
飲もう！
(ケンジ)いいとも！
Let's drink!
You bet!
さぁ 今日は ぶぁ～っと
盛り上がるぞ～！
Okay! I'm getting wasted tonight!
(店員)あの お客様？
Um, excuse me?
Yep! I'm listening!
はいはい！聞いてま～す！
海外通話 メールサービスの
ご利用は➡
Would you like to keep your international calling and e-mail service?
そのまま継続という
ことでよろしいですか？
よろしいですよ～！
Absolutely!
《♪～ ふん ふん ふん…➡
マジでふっふっふっ～》
I can't stop smiling.
《昨日は嬉しさのあまり
つい飲み過ぎちまった》
I drank too much last night because I was so happy.
《しかし…》
However...
Itou Serika
ありがとう ケンジ～！》
Thank you, Kenji!
《君のおかげで今➡
Itou Serika
Thanks to you,
せりかさんのアドレスが
俺の携帯に…》
Serika's e-mail address is in my phone!
Huh?
Unknown Number Incoming Call
《え!?ま まさか！》
Huh? Could it be?
《せりかさん!?》
Serika?
はい もしもし？
Yes, hello?
よう 久しぶり｡
Hey, it's been a while.
元気っぽいね ムッちゃん
その声の調子は｡
You sound like you're doing well, Mu.
まぁな｡訳あって 今元気だ｡
I guess so. I happen to be feeling good right now.
じゃあ二次試験の通過は
自信あるってことね｡
So you feel confident about passing the second exam?
そ それは…｡
W-Well...
((みんなより
シャンプーが泡立ちます))
...make more bubbles than anyone else when I lather my shampoo.
((あ あと リンスも泡立ちます))
I even make bubbles when I'm rinsing!
ウホン！当然だろ？
Of course!
二次試験くらいでコケるかよ｡
I'm not gonna drop out in the second round.
Man, how could I have said that?
《あ～ 言っちゃった～》
《いや いいんだこれで》
No, that was right.
((ここは 俺の場所だ！))
That is my spot!
《これでいい…俺は南波日々人の
お兄ちゃんで終わらねぇぞ》
That's the spirit!
I won't spend my entire life as "Nanba Hibito's older brother"!
《たぶんな》
I think...
So, can you come, Mu?
っていうことは こっちに
来るんだな ムッちゃん？
Huh? Y-Yeah, I'm coming!
[ｹｲﾀｲ]ん!?あ ああ 行くとも！
じゃあ 来週来なよ｡
How does next week sound?
へッ!?来週～!?
Huh?
Next week?
らいしゅう｡
Next week.
《何て急な話だ！》
That came out of nowhere.
((どうせ三次試験は何ヶ月も
先なんだからさ ムッちゃん➡
You have a few months before the third exam, Mu.
こっち来て訓練とか みんなの
仕事ぶりを見るチャンスだよ))
This is a chance to come and
do some training, and meet other astronauts.
((来週って…旅費とか何とか
こっちにも都合ってもんが…))
Next week?
I have my own life. Plus, it'll be expensive.
Expensive?
((旅費？そんなの
ＮＡＳＡもちだよ｡➡
NASA will pay for everything.
They cover expenses for family members.
家族は支援されるように
なってる))
《正直 日々人に会わせる
顔などないのだが…》
Honestly, I'm a little ashamed to see Hibito right now,
《ＮＡＳＡの誘惑に負けた！
しかもタダだし》
but I can't turn down a trip to NASA!
For free!
《ＮＡＳＡ ＮＡＳＡ
ＮＡＳＡ ＮＡＳＡ》
NASA... NASA... NASA... NASA...
NASA is calling to me!
《ＮＡＳＡが俺を呼んでいる！》
《♪～ ＮＡＳＡが
俺を呼んでいる》
NASA is calling to me!
I began singing
《そのフレーズが 頭の中で
歌に変わっていった》
that phrase in my mind...
NASA is calling to me!
《♪～ ＮＡＳＡが
俺を呼んでいる…》
The stars I admired were too bright for me
so I quietly closed my eyes
I have faith in you, as you stand alone, full of doubts
I'm right here, next to you
Come now, take my hand and hold it tight
If you do, we will always
have hope, shine with light
and overcome whatever we might face
Do you see how wonderful this world is
and how our future unfolds?
Even the tears we shed and could not put into words
will one day dry up, I am sure
One by one the smiles spread
and ascend towards the starlit sky
＜ＮＡＳＡが俺を呼んでいるって
ホントか？＞
Next time, on
Space Brothers
#05 Days of Missing
Is NASA really calling to me?
＜まっ 日々人の家族ってことで
タダだし➡
Well, the trip's free of charge, thanks to Hibito's family program.
俺は アメリカ ヒューストンへ＞
I'm off to Houston, USA!
＜月を目指す毎日を送る
日々人と再会する＞
To see Hibito, who's training for his lunar mission.
＜けど やっぱ あいつ
ネジ１本 足りないなぁ＞
But he's got a screw loose.
＜久しぶりだな｡ムッちゃんも
月 行くんだろ？＞
It's been a while.
Aren't you headed to the moon?
＜簡単に言ってくれるぜ＞
You make it sound so easy.
＜今は もう お前とじゃ
立場が違いすぎるんだよ➡
We're in totally different worlds now.
月までの距離も＞
And yours is a lot closer to the moon.
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"Days of Missing."
＜ムッちゃん もっと張り合えよ＞
Mu, you're supposed to be my rival.
パンパカパーン！
This Week's Space Photo
Visit the official website (uchukyodai.com) for more details.
This week's space photo!
今週の宇宙写真です！
スッゲェ！
Awesome!